所以逆变函子是对它们的第一个值进行操作的函子。
So contravariant functors are functors that operate on their first value.
所以如果我有一个从 a 到字符串的函数，
So if I have a function from a to string,
是的，我知道它总是会返回一个字符串。
right, and I know it will always return me a string.
但我可以接受任何一个开始。
But I can take in any a to begin with.
我可以映射 a 并将其转换为 ab，但它总是以字符串结尾。
I can map over the a and turn it into a b but it will always end up on a string.
所以一个例子，和
SO an example of that, and
我们可以用排序函数、谓词函数来做到这一点。
we could do this with sort functions, predicate functions.
谓词函数接受任何东西并返回一个布尔值，对，
Predicate functions take in anything and return a Bool, right,
排序函数返回 -1、0、1 或其他值的枚举。
sorting functions return an enum of -1, 0, 1, or something.
但是我们能够映射到论点，并且
But we're able to map over to the argument, and
这有点像超能力，对吧？
this is kind of like a superpower, right?
所以如果我从一个函数开始
So if I start off with a function,
让我们做 Reducer 因为那有点有趣。
let's do Reducer because that one's kinda fun.
所以这需要，我会说运行。
So this takes, I'll say run.
而且，Reducer 持有什么？
And, what is Reducer holding?
这是一个累加器和一个 x 或
It's a taking an accumulator and an x or
一些返回一个新的累加器，对吗？
some a returning a new accumulator, right?
所以，蓄能器固定。
So, accumulators fixed.
我无法映射它，它无法改变它。
I can't map over it, it can't change that.
但是它可以将这些值中的每一个更改为 ab 因为这并不重要，
But it can change each of these values a to a b cuz it doesn't really matter,
以便它设置为我可以映射的输入类型。
so that it sets like an input type that I can map over.
所以让我们继续建模Reducers。
So let's go ahead and model Reducers.
我们公开了一个运行函数。
And we have a run function exposed.
我们有一个连接。
And we have a concat.
那么让我们看看如何连接两个Reducer。
So let's just so how we can concat two Reducers.
我们可以带一个减速器，我实际上不会提供你可以
We could take a Reducer, I'm actually not gonna deliver that you can
只需通过合并累加器或选择一个或另一个来连接两个 Reducer。
concat two Reducers just by merging the accumulators or picking one or the other.
让我们做违禁品。
Let's do contramap.
这是我们关注的事情。
This is the thing we're focused on.
所以， contramap 需要一个函数 f。
So, contramap takes a function f.
而不是在我们映射输出的地方写地图，
And instead of writing map where we would map over the output,
我们要映射输入，看起来像。
we're gonna map over the input, does that look like.
我们正在返回一个新的 Reducer，因为我们正在映射，
We're returning a new Reducer because we're mapping,
我们拿我们的累加器和我们的价值。
we take our accumulator and our value.
我们将在累加器上运行我们的东西，然后
And we're gonna run our thing on the accumulator, and
我们会在它到达之前击中那个 x。
we're gonna hit that x before it ever gets there.
所以，我们所做的是在值到达我们的函数之前对其进行转换。
So, what we've done is transformed the value before it got to our function.
我们能够做这些违禁品。
And we're able to do these contramaps.
如果您有一堆要组合的功能，这将很有用。
And that is useful if you have a bunch of functions you're gonna combine.
所以，我可以做一些Reducer。
So, I can make a few Reducers.
我们可以在这里快速编写 concat，但是假设我们有像 login 一样的 Reducer。
We could write concat here real quick, but let's say we have Reducer like login.
另一个我们要连接
And another we're gonna concat
使用 Reducer 就像更改页面或其他什么一样。
that with a Reducer that's like change page or whatever.
问题是如果我想像有效载荷一样运行它，
And the thing is if I wanna run this with just like a payload,
只是某种喜欢，让我们说这就像动作。
just some kind of like, let's say this is like the action.
它有一个用户，用户有一堆东西，
It has a user and the user has a bunch of stuff and
它就像一个环境，里面有很多东西。
it's got like an environment and that's got a bunch of stuff.
当我能够做的实际上是限制这些功能中的每一个并且
When I'm able to do is actually contramap each of these functions and
实际上从有效载荷中提取值。
actually pluck values off the payload.
所以我们会在这里获取用户，然后我们连接
So we'll get the user here, And then we concat
更改页面应该带我们使它成为路由器或当前页面。
that with change page which should take us make this the router or the current page.
更改页面应该会违禁
Change page should will contramap
有效载荷并获取当前页面。
the payload and taken the current page.
好的，我们已经完成了两个Reducers的组合，它们都有
All right so, we've done is combined two Reducers, both of them have
提前被限制以获取这一输入并将其转换为
been contramapped in advance to take this one input and transform it into
他们实际上正在寻找什么作为其功能的输入。
what they're actually looking for as an input to their functions.
然后，我用一些状态和一些新的有效载荷运行它，
And then, I'm running it with some state and some payload new,
获取所有这些并运行它。
get all those and run it.
所以重点是， contramap 在它进来之前就命中参数。
So the point is, contramap hits arguments before it comes in.
这是练习的一部分。
That's part of the exercises.
所以我想说出来。
So I wanted to call that out.
有人对 contramap 的工作原理有任何疑问吗？
Does anybody have any questions on how contramap works?
很酷，这很顺利，事情很难。
Cool, this is going swimmingly, stuff is hard.
[笑]好吧，所以我们有，是吗？
[LAUGH] All right, so we have, yes?
&gt;&gt; 所以 contramap 的目的是保持整个有效载荷的运行
&gt;&gt; So the purpose of contramap is to keep the entire payload going
通过这个系统，但是把东西摘下来并传递给内部函数？
through this system, but plucking things off and passing it to inner functions?
&gt;&gt; 这是个好问题。
&gt;&gt; That's a good question.
这是你可以做的一个用例，你可以说就像我结合了一堆
That is one use case you can do, you can say like I'm combining a bunch of
函数，但它们都采用不同的输入，对吗？
functions but they all take different inputs, right?
在我组合了所有功能后，我将调用 run 一次。
And I'm gonna call run once after I've combined all my functions.
所以这是我使用减速器说的一个用例，嘿，你有所有
So this is one use case I was using reducers to say like, hey, you have all
您组合的这些减速器，但它们都采用不同的输入。
these reducers that you've combined but they all take different inputs.
好吧，我们可以在他们到达之前禁止地图。
Well we can contramap before they get there.
所以如果你把功能合二为一
So if you're combining functions into one,
你可能想在他们到达之前操纵东西。
you might wanna manipulate stuff before they get there.
这提供了它几乎就像一个前钩子。
And this provides it's almost like a before hook.
而地图就像一个后钩。
Whereas map would be like an after hook.
所以这让你有能力进入那里并
So that gives you the ability to kind of get in there and
在论点到来之前改变论点。
change the argument before it arrives.
这往往只在你结合的情况下才有用
And that tends to really only be useful in situations where you're combining
功能合二为一，它们都采用相同的输入。
functions into one and they all take the same input.
它在您有固定输出的情况下也很有用
And it's also useful in situations where you have a fixed output
固定输出是静态的，但输入不是，你可以
and the fixed output is static, but the input is not, and you're able
预组合而不是后组合能够构建应用程序。
to pre-compose instead of post compose to be able to build out applications.